### Jhaura Wachsman

## Web Developer, Internet Marketer

Jhaura is a senior level web developer with management skills which allows him to interface directly with clients and communicate effectively. His reputation for accuracy, timeliness and honesty make Jhaura an asset to the project.

Core Areas of Expertise: Web Development (LAMP), PHP, MySQL, Wordpress (Templates, Plugins and Integration), Responsive frameworks (Foundation & Bootstrap), HTML5, CSS3 (Compass & SaSS), eCommerce, SSL, SEO, Internet Marketing, Email Marketing, Direct Marketing, Affiliate Marketing, Facebook Apps, Social Media integration and niche/startup business development.

**Tools Used**: Sublime Text editor. Git version control. Ruby, Gem development environment. Photoshop & Illustrator CS. Google Adwords and Adsense, Microsoft AdCenter. Amazon AWS and Cloudfront CDN. Amazon Seller and Ads. Google Analytics and Webmaster tools for understanding where profit can be made from traffic and where more value can be created for users.

# **Experience**

## Web Developer, Internet Marketer at Consultant

June 2005 - Present (8 years)

Web Development and Programming

- Wordpress EXPERT, Joomla, Drupal and Magento strengths
- Nine years hand coding PHP (OOP), MySQL, HTML, JavaScript and CSS
- Full knowledge of WC3 standards for authoring validated code
- Section 508 and WAI relating to the Americans with Disabilities Act
- Demonstrated work in Internationalization (i18n) and Localization (I10n)
- Eight years SSL, credit card authorization and E-Commerce experience
- Amazon AWS and Cloudfront CDN (Content Delivery Network)
- Skilled in session management, cookies, frames, forms and debugging

#### Web Design

- Nine years Photoshop/Image Ready, Flash and Illustrator design experience
- Expert at making Web pages load faster with image optimization and slices
- Able to bridge the gap between design and coding departments
- Re/designed over 50 Websites and over 100 graphic email newsletters

#### Email Newsletter Design, Development and Systems

- Photoshop design and HTML/CSS coding 100s of HTML/Text email newsletters
- Experience with all major ESPs such as Constant Contact and Aweber
- User experience, web-mail and Outlook tested designs and code
- Email newsletter optimization to decrease bandwidth costs

- Proven profit making campaigns with Google Adwords, Yahoo! and Microsoft
- Ebay, Amazon Seller, Ads, Associates and API setup and integration
- PPC, CPM, Adsense, banners, direct mail and email marketing channels
- Keyword research, market analysis, niche discovery and intelligence
- Google Analytics custom report creation for conversion performance
- Tapping every last drop of ROI and profit from revenue sources
- SEO for natural search ranking and user experience
- Facebook, Twitter social media App building and integration

#### Linux System Administration

• Six years Linux system administration experience - local and remote

## Principal, Founder, Web Developer/Programmer at Consultlogic, Inc.

April 2000 - January 2005 (4 years 10 months)

Conceptualized, engineered and programmed PHP/MySQL Web application credited for generating 95% of the business revenue. Setup, optimized, secured and maintained multiple local and remote Linux file, database, email and Web servers responsible for running the core business applications with 99.9% uptime. Simultaneously served as president, CEO, software engineer and customer service agent for four years.

- Created one of the earliest Email Publishing cloud-based services similar to Constant Contact
- Became known as an expert in email publishing and HTML email
- Consulted by numerous authors and industry experts on email publishing
- Solely responsible for tripling new customer growth in two quarters
- Designed and coded over 100 HTML email newsletters and over 50 Websites
- Conducted usability and QA testing on over 50 MUAs (mail user agents)

# Adjunct Web Development/Design Instructor at Santa Barbara City College

December 2001 - January 2003 (1 year 2 months)

Created Web-based curriculum for MAT 108 Web Design Tools & Techniques and MAT 122 Web Design I. Instructed both courses in semester format lasting close to four months each. Quickly earned a reputation for being a precise and knowledgeable instructor of Web design and development.

Created three department websites, including the SBCC Radio property. Provided implementation strategy on web initiatives, Internet business development, web design and web standards to staff.

- · Curriculum is still used today by subsequent instructors
- Students successfully published over 30 live Websites each class
- Brought in local industry leaders and experts to share experiences
- Helped with student job placement and internships at local companies
- Improved and polished public speaking and presentation skills

# Web Product Manager at The Hendricks Institute, Inc.

July 1999 - May 2001 (1 year 11 months)

Project manager responsible for IIS/SQL E-Commerce site deployment. Implemented marketing strategies through Affiliate Marketing increasing product placement on the Web. Deployed and managed third-party email marketing solution which increased seminar enrollment and product sales each month. Developed vendor and consumer relations policies centered around customer satisfaction.

- Designed and coded graphically rich HTML marketing emails
- Designed product graphics and copy for use in E-Commerce and marketing
- Produced CD, VHS, cassette and book products sold internationally
- Presented new products at seminars to groups of 20–100 people

## Store Manager at Channel Islands Surfboards

June 1990 - July 1998 (8 years 2 months)

Started out as Sales Associate, promoted to manager. Managed a team of 10 crew members under high-stress peak season retail conditions. Successfully cultivated a new era of customer service excellence by setting personal examples with difficult customers. Known as the 'goto' person who could make even the most irate customer return happy and satisfied.

- Contributed to sales increases of 50-500% in key departments
- Exceeded each days sales goals on a regular basis
- Worked with sales representatives in store and at trade shows
- · Created a high standard of customer service

### **Education**

## University of California, Santa Barbara

- Bachelor of Arts, Religious Studies, 1996 1998
- Certificate, eCommerce, Web Development and Design, 2000 2001
- Activities and Societies: Study abroad in India. Extension studies for professional development.

# Santa Barbara City College

- Associate of Arts, Liberal Studies / Spanish, 1993 1996
- Activities and Societies: Study abroad in Mexico. Presidential honors.

### **Interests**

Surfing, ultralight backpacking, meditation, traveling the world and gardening. Nature, the ocean and rivers, spirituality, Helping others create abundance in their lives. Philanthropy.

#### **Recommendations from LinkedIn**

"Jhaura provided the necessary expertise that we lacked with our staff. Through a dedication to getting the job done right and training our staff, Jhaura left us with a better web presence than we could have ever expected."

- Stephen DaVega, Chair Multimedia Dept., Santa Barbara City College

- "Jhaura explained everything in detail and it was really a pleasure to work with him. I hope we have the chance to work together again."
- Daniela Dimitrova, Graphic Designer
- "Jhaura has outstanding capabilities and capacities as exemplified in his personality and his educational, technical and organizational achievements. With his background experiences, Jhaura utilizes the highest self motivation for goal accomplishment yet also exhibits an unselfish desire which empowers him to seek resources that will aide in the advancement and eventual success of the task at hand."
- Douglas Galati, Advisor, Board of Directors, Carpinteria Skate Foundation
- "I have worked with Jhaura for a year and a half. I have always found him to be competent, enthusiastic, and accessible. Jhaura is a person who has a lot of wonderful ideas about business, and is extremely generous with them, always. But probably the most important thing I can say about Jhaura is that he is a person of high integrity at all times, and in all circumstances."
- Felicia Saunders, Sales Manager, Zrii
- "Jhaura is a dedicated and innovative leader. He is always looking for ways to improve and expand himself, his business, and the people he works with. If you want to stay one step ahead, you should consider working with Jhaura. Top Notch!"
- Doug Conklin, Sales Manager, Zrii
- "Thorough, smart and dedicated to making things happen. Jhaura is someone you want to associated with."
- Don Campbell, President, Inside Out Landscapes